<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tf datalab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tf datalab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internationality and the Role of Domestic Knowledge Pools</title>
      <link>/2018/11/03/internationality-in-innovation-networks-and-the-size-of-domestic-knowledge-pools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/03/internationality-in-innovation-networks-and-the-size-of-domestic-knowledge-pools/</guid>
      <description>The Role of Domestic Knowledge PoolsIn a previous post (link here), I hypothesized that internationality in innovation networks is negatively related to the size of the domestic knowledge pool. Countries with a small domestic knowledge pools can be expected to depend on foreign co-operation in many areas of research, whereas countries with large innovative capacities probably have many of the necessary innovative resource within national borders. This post aims to substantiate this logic with some quantitative arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internationality in Innovation Networks</title>
      <link>/2018/10/26/internationality-in-innovation-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/26/internationality-in-innovation-networks/</guid>
      <description>Country dispersion in patent applicationsThe TPF database contains data on the country of origin of patent application (country of residence of the inventor(s) and country of the applying organizations). This allows for interesting investigations into country-specific aspects of innovative activity. In this post I will investigate the issue of country dispersion in patent data. Country dispersion is a measure of the degree of internationality of patent applications. According to Lee (2016), the country dispersion index is calculated as \[D = 1 - \sum_{i=1}^N S^2_{i}\] where \(N\) is the number of countries involved in a patent and \(S_i\) is the share of inventors located in country \(i\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patent Analysis Using R</title>
      <link>/2018/07/09/patent-analysis-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/09/patent-analysis-using-r/</guid>
      <description>I created this blog to illustrate some of my learning efforts in R programming. Studying R, I found it much easier to practice the language by applying it to real-world datasets instead of textbook examples. The first dataset I use for some experimentation is the OECD Triadic Patent Families Database. This dataset provides endless possibilities for quantitative analyses in the realm of innovation studies and intellectual property statistics.
What is the OECD Triadic Patent Families Database?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog deals with intellectual property statistics and other data analyses in R. It was built using the blogdown package for R. The theme is the example theme from blogdown and was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.
This project is a learning experience for me in making and maintaining a statical website, as well as R and statistical analyses. While I will try to present interesting analyses and code examples, the contents should be taken with a grain of salt, as I have little experience in the matters I deal with here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>